<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on CRASHLOGS</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on CRASHLOGS</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Blog Post</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/formatting/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/formatting/</guid>
            <description>👋 Welcome to My Blog Hey there!
Welcome to my very first post on this Hugo-powered blog.
✨ Why I Started This Blog I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted a place to:
🛠 Document my projects 📚 Share what I learn 🌐 Connect with others 🧭 What You&amp;rsquo;ll Find Here Tech tutorials Build logs Creative experiments Personal thoughts from time to time 💡 “Start where you are. Use what you have. Do what you can.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="-welcome-to-my-blog">👋 Welcome to My Blog</h1>
<p><em>Hey there!</em><br>
Welcome to my very first post on this Hugo-powered blog.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="-why-i-started-this-blog">✨ Why I Started This Blog</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always wanted a place to:</p>
<ul>
<li>🛠 <em>Document my projects</em></li>
<li>📚 <em>Share what I learn</em></li>
<li>🌐 <em>Connect with others</em></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="-what-youll-find-here">🧭 What You&rsquo;ll Find Here</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Tech tutorials</strong></li>
<li><strong>Build logs</strong></li>
<li><strong>Creative experiments</strong></li>
<li><em>Personal thoughts from time to time</em></li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p>💡 <em>“Start where you are. Use what you have. Do what you can.”</em> — Arthur Ashe</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="-code-snippets">🔧 Code Snippets</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s how you print something in Go:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-go" data-lang="go"><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#f92672">package</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">main</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#f92672">import</span> <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;fmt&#34;</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#66d9ef">func</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">main</span>() {
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#a6e22e">fmt</span>.<span style="color:#a6e22e">Println</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;Hello, world!&#34;</span>)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>}
</span></span></code></pre></div>]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Why I still rock my iPod</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rockmyipod/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rockmyipod/</guid>
            <description>Listen up, music lovers! I&amp;rsquo;m still clutching my iPod like a digital treasure in a world where Spotify, Apple Music, and YouTube reign supreme, But this isn&amp;rsquo;t some hipster nostalgia trip &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s a conscious choice that&amp;rsquo;s cooler and smarter than you might think.
Not because I hate change. But because it&amp;rsquo;s better &amp;ndash; for me, for the planet, and to fight digital enshitification.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get real about music consumption in 2025.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Listen up,</strong> <em>music lovers!</em> I&rsquo;m still clutching my iPod like a digital treasure in a world where Spotify, Apple Music, and YouTube reign supreme, But this isn&rsquo;t some hipster nostalgia trip &ndash; it&rsquo;s a conscious choice that&rsquo;s cooler and smarter than you might think.</p>
<p>Not because I hate change. But because it&rsquo;s <em>better</em> &ndash; for me, for the planet, and to <strong>fight digital enshitification.</strong></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s get real about music consumption in 2025. Here&rsquo;s why I still rock my iPod instead of relying on streaming apps, and why you might want to reconsider your daily music habits too.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="1-streaming--massive-energy-drain">1. <strong>Streaming = Massive Energy Drain</strong></h3>
<p>Streaming music isn&rsquo;t just <em>listening over Wi-Fi.</em> it looks convenient, but it&rsquo;s basically an energy monster hiding behind a sleek interface.</p>
<p>Every time you hit <strong>play</strong>, you&rsquo;re triggering a massive behind-the-scenes performance: servers wake up, data centers hum, and electricity starts dancing. Imagine a million people streaming the same 3-minute track we&rsquo;re talking terabytes of bandwidth getting pushed around, with cooling systems working overtime and hardware sweating bullets.</p>
<p>These servers run 24/7 in data centers powered by huge amounts of electricity. Multiply this by billions of users, and suddenly your playlist is part of a <strong>global carbon footprint.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h3 id="2-local-files-use-zero-network-energy">2. <strong>Local Files Use Zero Network Energy</strong></h3>
<p>My iPod? Total rebel. Zero network energy. Zero drama, the music is already there. No Wi-Fi. No cellular data. No server ping. Just good old local playback, which means my listening habits don’t add a single watt to global bandwidth consumption.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="3-offline-music--greener-music">3. <strong>Offline Music = Greener Music</strong></h3>
<p>Picture this: the sweet satisfaction of downloading your favorite tune just once. Each play afterwards is a harmony that echoes without draining our planet.</p>
<p>Streaming, by contrast, is like a DJ who insists on rebuying the track for every encore. Press play ten times a week? That&rsquo;s ten downloads, unless you’re savvy enough to switch to offline mode.</p>
<p>This isn’t brand-new; it’s simply that trusty old iPod in disguise, quietly hosting your hits. By embracing offline music, you&rsquo;re not just serenading your soul; you’re also composing a greener planet, one play at a time!</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="4-ipods-dont-snoop">4. <strong>iPods Don’t Snoop</strong></h3>
<p>I&rsquo;m not just being a tech contrarian I&rsquo;m making a statement about digital sustainability. While everyone else is drowning in algorithmic recommendations and endless playlists, I&rsquo;m enjoying pure, uninterrupted music ownership. My device doesn&rsquo;t know my mood, doesn&rsquo;t track my location, and definitely doesn&rsquo;t try to sell me anything. It just plays music. Revolutionary, right?</p>
<p>Streaming apps track everything &ndash; your location, listening time, habits, moods. It’s not just music, it’s surveillance made up to produce more “sellable” tunes. My iPod? It doesn’t know anything about me. It just plays the music I put on it. <em>That’s freedom.</em></p>
<hr>
<h3 id="5-no-ads-no-algorithmic-bs">5. <strong>No Ads, No Algorithmic BS</strong></h3>
<p>Streaming apps push ads, recommendations, and playlists you didn’t ask for — all in the name of engagement. On my iPod, I’m in control. No distractions. No <em>suggested for you</em> content. Just my music, my vibe.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="6-battery-efficiency-ftw">6. <strong>Battery Efficiency FTW</strong></h3>
<p>Battery life is another epic win. My iPod runs forever on a single charge, while smartphone users are constantly hunting for outlets. Those streaming apps? Total battery vampires, sucking power through background syncs and constant data transmission.</p>
<p>By listening to music on offline dedicated devices, I charge once a week at worst and I do not risk being unreachable on my phone because I felt an urge to smash my ears with some Alice Cooper in transports</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="7-ipods-still-sound-great">7. <strong>iPods Still Sound Great</strong></h3>
<p>Sound quality matters too. With high-bitrate MP3s or FLACs and solid headphones, my iPod delivers audio that makes most compressed streaming formats sound like they&rsquo;re singing through a tin can. Most people don&rsquo;t even realize <strong>how much audio quality they&rsquo;re sacrificing for &ldquo;convenience.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<hr>
<h3 id="8-bandwidth-isnt-infinite">8. <strong>Bandwidth Isn’t Infinite</strong></h3>
<p>The sustainability angle is crucial. Every streaming session is an <strong>invisible carbon footprint.</strong> Network infrastructure, data centers, constant data transfers — it all adds up. By choosing local media, I&rsquo;m making a <em>micro-choice</em> that actually matters for our digital ecosystem. Playing local music = zero load on those systems.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="9-a-form-of-digital-minimalism">9. <strong>A Form of Digital Minimalism</strong></h3>
<p>Using an iPod is a <strong>small rebellion.</strong> It separates music from the smartphone vortex. I&rsquo;m not stuck in 2007. I&rsquo;m living in 2025 with a mindset that values <strong>intentionality</strong>, privacy, and environmental consciousness. My iPod isn&rsquo;t just a device &ndash; it&rsquo;s a statement</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="10-one-less-subscription">10. <strong>One Less Subscription</strong></h3>
<p>And let&rsquo;s talk money. While everyone&rsquo;s <strong>juggling monthly subscriptions,</strong> I&rsquo;m buying music once and owning it forever. No disappearing albums. No changing licensing deals. Just pure, unadulterated music ownership.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="your-call"><strong>Your call</strong></h3>
<p>We often overlook the <em>hidden cost of convenience.</em> Streaming feels free, but it’s powered by massive energy-hungry infrastructures — server farms, network switches, cell towers. As we become more conscious of digital sustainability, using local media is a smart and impactful micro-choice.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>and most of that is storage for collected data on you to better sell you the next Cardi.B solo</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>So yeah, I still rock my iPod.</strong></p>
<p><em>(And I am really not a big fan of Apple)</em></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
